README
numerical_analysis

Contact Sarah Flanagan (sflanagan@bio.tamu.edu) for more information.

Runs a numerical analysis as described in Flanagan & Jones. 
It assumes a population size of 1000 individuals per deme, 2000 replications (genes), and 5000 generations.
50 individuals are sampled from each sampled populations.
Sampling either occurs as a certain number of samples per population or by randomly-sampling populations (a single population could be sampled multiple times).
Required input:
1. Base output file name, including the path
2. Nm (population size = 1000 times the migration rate)
3. The number of demes
4. The number of populations to sample
5. Whether random sampling is turned on or off.

What it outputs:
1. Average Allele frequencies, Fsts, etc. for each generation (*.freqs.txt).
2. Heterozygosities, Fsts, and average allele frequency for all demes (not the sampled populations) for each locus at the end of the 5000 generations (*.output.txt).
3. Heterozygosities, Fsts, and average allele frequency calculated from the sampled populations (whether populations were randomly sampled or not) for each locus (*.sampledpops.txt).
4. Genepop file for the sampled output, ready to be input to LOSITAN.


Installation and Usage:
Windows:
Put the executable (numerical_analysis.exe) in a useful folder. It is easiest (the path you must provide is shortest) if you put it in your desired output directory.

Ubuntu:
Put the executable in a useful folder. It is easiest (the path you must provide is shortest) if you put it in your desired output directory.
**You may need to alter file permissions for it to run:
chmod u+x numerical_analysis

To run the file in interactive mode: 
./numerical_analysis

To run the file with arguments:
./numerical_analysis -o file_name_base_ -n 0.1 -d 100 -s 10 -r y

For help:
./numerical_analysis -h 

Other operating systems:
Compile the source code using the g++ compiler.
For example:
g++ numerical_analysis.cpp -o numerical_analysis -std=c++0x


Arguments:
-o	base file name (include path). Example: N1000_s10_
-n	Nm
-d	number of subpopulations/demes
-r	random sample? y to turn random sampling on or n to turn random sampling off
-s	number of populations to sample
-h	display this message
no arguments:	interactive mode